Soviet Union Registered Baptists Subject Files, Inclusive: 1890-2006, undated, Bulk: 1961-1998
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
- General, 1890-2006, undated; 1
  - Registered Baptist Church Members' Defection, Emigration on Religious Grounds, 1963-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Registered Baptist Church Samizdat. General, 1975-1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Underground" Production of Registered Baptist Church Literature, 1909-1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Underground" Production of Registered Baptist Church Literature. "Pislanets Pravdy", 1976-1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Registered Baptist Church Charitable Activity, 1969-2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Registered Baptist Church Theology, Philosophy, Education, and Ethics, 1962-1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Registered Baptist Church Theology, 1960-1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Individual Baptist Theologians. Alf Dickson's Three Leaflets on Christianity, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Religion and Science, Medicine, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Ethics and Morality, 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Theological Education, 1967-1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Theological Education, 1979-1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Religious Education of Children, 1969-1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Religion and Intelligentsia, 1957-1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Unity, Schisms, Doctrinal Differences, 1960-1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Philosophy of Unity, 1970-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Heresy, Cults, Schisms, 1967-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Registered Baptist Church Statistics, 1951-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Registered Baptist Church Statistics, 1977-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Relations with Fellow Believers (1 of 2), 1967-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Relations with Fellow Believers (1 of 2), 1977-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Relations with Fellow Believers. Individuals, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Ecumenical Relations with Other Denominations (1 of 2), 1964-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Ecumenical Relations with Other Denominations (2 of 2), 1961-1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Ecumenical Contacts with Denominations Outside the Soviet Union (1 of 2), 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Ecumenical Contacts with Denominations Outside the Soviet Union (2 of 2), 1974-1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Relations with the World Council of Churches, 1972-1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Ecumenical Contacts with Denominations Within Soviet Union, 1976-1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Religion and National Identity, 1972-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Pronouncements on Secular Affairs, 1972-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Peace Activities, 1972-1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Registered Baptist Church's Peace Activities. Christian Peace Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Registered Baptist Church Music, 1973-1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Registered Baptist Church Literature (1 of 2), 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Registered Baptist Church Literature (2 of 2), 1990-2000 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Registered Baptist Church Literature. Bible, 1978-1991 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Registered Baptist Church Women, 1968-1991 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Registered Baptist Church Youth and Children, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Sociological Surveys, 1965-1975 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Visual Material, 1965-1974 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Samizdat, 1965-1988, undated; 2
  The Registered Baptist Samizdat Subject Files contain materials pertaining to the persecution of Registered Baptist Church members fighting for their freedom of religion. The most notable case is on the arrest and persecution of Russian Christian rock musician Valerii Barinov, the author of Christian rock opera “The Trumpet Call.” The files consist of unofficially circulated documents, reports, appeals, addresses, original and translated literary works, and underground religious literature which never passed through Soviet censorship and were not officially published. The series is in good condition.
  - Individual Members of Registered Baptist Church. Barinov, Valerii, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Registered Baptist Church Administration. Individual Churches. Chernovtsy, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Registered Baptist Church Administration. All-Union Council of Evangelical Baptists-Christians, 1983 November (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Registered Baptist Church Administration. The 42nd Congress of the All-Union Council of Evangelical Baptists-Christians, 1979 December (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Protests, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Samizdat Texts. Gortfeld, G.G., Diary, ca. 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Samizdat Texts. Gethsemane Baptist Church, Riga, Latvia, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Underground Religious Literature. Vozvyshennyi polet, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Underground Religious Music. Rock Opera “The Trumpet Call” (1 of 5), 1971-1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Underground Religious Music. Rock Opera “The Trumpet Call” (2 of 5), undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Underground Religious Music. Rock Opera “The Trumpet Call” (3 of 5), ca. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Underground Religious Music. Rock Opera “The Trumpet Call” (4 of 5), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Registered Baptist Church. Underground Religious Music. Rock Opera “The Trumpet Call” (5 of 5), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)